

☑ nick@ncronquist.com ② ncronquist.com ८ (206) 886-1432 У nicholaibee in ncronquist ۞ ncronquist

summary

Software engineer with 8+ years experience leading teams to develop, deploy, and manage web services. Passionate about building platforms and tools to help development teams be more productive. Former consultant with experience determining priorities and balancing business and technical needs. Always excited to learn new things.

> skills

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

JavaScript (Node.js)

Experience with Bash, Golang, Ruby, Python, Groovy, and SQL

DATABASE TOOLSElasticsearch
Microsoft SQL Server

Redis

OTHER TECHNOLOGIES AND SKILLS

Docker GraphQL OTHER TECHNOLOGIES AND SKILLS

AWS Kubernetes

Continuous Integration and Delivery (CircleCI and Jenkins)



Elixir

employment

SAP Concur

Software Design Engineer

Bellevue, WA Aug. 2015 to Current

Worked on multiple teams designing and building distributed systems with end-to-end ownership of services. Projects focused on moving Concur from a monolithic architecture to a service oriented architecture. Promoted automation of tests, builds, and deployments on all projects to increase velocity and improve confidence in changes. Mentored junior developers and conducted technical hiring interviews.

Client Data Services (CDS)

GraphQL PaaS allowing developers to deploy small pieces of a GraphQL schema. Contributed to all parts of the CDS platform including the base engine and local emulator written in NodeJS, management CLI written in Golang, and the AWS and Kubernetes infrastructure. Implemented the initial resolver stitching and added support for remote schemas; a key part of the local emulator.

Orchestration

GraphQL service exposing Concur API data to the Concur UI teams. Organized a complex data model into an easier to consume view model. Used view model designs to create a GraphQL schema and associated resolver code written in Elixir. Improved the reliability of the service through better automation and monitoring, support for asynchronous mutations, and more resilient code handling of upstream API requests.

Receipts

HATEOS driven REST API that manages receipts at Concur. Implemented queuing and event processing for all I/O actions to improve fault tolerance and to increase performance through parallel processing. Improved image generation process and built functional tests that greatly reduced bug frequency. Automated Kubernetes deployments dealing with both stateful and stateless resources. Managed date, time, and other globalization issues for a service used by clients around the world.

Fast Enterprises

Implementation Consultant, E-Services Lead

Vientiane, Laos Mar. 2013 to Dec. 2014

Oversaw the design and development of the Laos e-services taxpayer website. Managed fluctuating project requirements and variable time schedules to help Laos meet WTO standards. Designed and implemented processes for taxpayers to register vehicles and to securely upload attachments to client servers.

Integrated antivirus protection into the e-services environment. Converted data from the client's legacy systems to Fast Enterprises' Gentax system.

Implementation Consultant, Registration and Collections

Baton Rouge, LA Jan. 2011 to Mar. 2013

Programmed complex redesign to suspend the licenses of individuals with delinquent tax liabilities. Developed and maintained several data warehouse entities. Created discovery processes based on data warehouse information to find new or missed revenue sources. Produced data cubes, reports, and ad hoc queries to help the government agencies retrieve useful information from their data.



education

General Assembly Web Development Immersive 2015

University of North Dakota

Bachelor of Business Administration Information Systems 2010